## Waleed Yasin Khan

Phone No.: +92-300-7366897 (Whatsapp) | +92-316-4463337

Email: waleed.yk07@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/waleed-khan-44527388

#### **O**BJECTIVE

Seeking a job to contribute my role towards the goal of the organization while using knowledge and practical skills.

#### SUMMARY

**Fullstack software developer** with overall experience of **08 years** in **05 different organizations** plus **02 times rebadging** and consultant/freelance work in multiple startups. Has a hands-on experience on multiple technology stacks and has worked in all software development phases. Has led a team of software developers and participated in architectural design activities.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



#### Jazz - PMCL, Islamabad

September 2022 Till Date

## **Expert Digital Products**

Responsibilities;-

- Gathering and evaluation requirements shared by the growth team for the self-service app "Jazz World"
- Writing business requirement documents precisely and clearly for Jazz World app to share with the development teams.
- Establish acceptance criteria and write test cases accordingly.
- Reviewing solution draft and suggesting modifications if required.
- Planning Deliveries.
- Successfully implemented Jazz World App regression pipeline to ensure app performance as per business needs and identify issues daily.
- Following up on action items.

- Coordination with multiple teams to ensure smooth delivery.
- Successfully mapped firebase events in the OTT app "Tamasha" and integrated with BigQuery.

afiniti.

### Afiniti Ltd., Islamabad

January 2022 Till September 2022

## <u>Senior Software Development Engineer for</u> <u>Test</u>

Responsibilities;-

- Worked in the Media Server team of Mega ACD project.
- Responsible for designing and implementing media server testing solutions for regression and sanity testing.
- Engage and coordinate with cross teams to identify and rectify fixtures in case of bugs report.

systems

## Systems Limited, Islamabad Rebadged from Telenor Pakistan

April 2020 to March 2021

## Advisory Software Engineer Responsibilities;-

- End to End ownership of TP APIGW and DaaS, including planning and stakeholder management.
- Oversee and manage the design and implementation of new applications.
- Ensure quality coding standards and documentation.



## Telenor Pakistan, Islamabad

February 2018 to April 2020

Software Development Specialist

#### Responsibilities;-

- Writing well-designed, testable, and efficient code.
- Take part in software and architectural development activities.
- Gather requirements from Telenor Group Partners; Google, Facebook, Trulio, and other partners for integration with Telenor Pakistan API-Gateway.
- Design and Develop Restful API Wrapper Services to be exposed online.
- Draft technical documentation for partners for successful integration with the TP platform.
- Successful end-to-end migration of the APIGEE platform in the fusion data center.
- Developed a thorough understanding of Google Dialog flow and ran successful POC of TP Services using Google Assistant (AoG).
- End to End Development of Contact Center IVR, from Scoping to Development and production deployment.
- End to End Development of Greenfield project - DaaS (Data as a Service) platform, including frontend single page application and backend services.



Apollo Telecom - Huawei Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (Telenor IPCC Project), Lahore

Rebadged from Huawei Technologies

November 2016 to February 2018

## <u>Sr. Support Associate – Huawei Contact Center</u> <u>MS</u>

Responsibilities:-

- Develop and Modify Skill Queue Routing Strategies as per Business requirement.
- Engage in Developing and Debugging IVR flows with the Telenor IVR development team
- Support in the Integration of GFEP nodes with 3rd party platforms.
- Configure Dtproxy to transfer GFEP output to IVR.
- Develop an understanding of 3rd party platforms to integrate with IPCC nodes.

- Troubleshoot all IVR and integrations-related issues and provide timely resolutions.
- Customize BICP reports.
- Solve BICP reports-related issues.
- Gather business requirements and attend meetings with the planning team to develop end-to-end understanding to be engaged in CR development and deployment till successful launch.



Huawei Technologies Pvt. Ltd. – People Pvt. Ltd. (Telenor IPCC Project), Lahore

August 2015 to November 2016

## <u>SLM Engineer – Huawei Contact Center MS</u> *Responsibilities:-*

- Manage ongoing CRs.
- Document Customer requirements.
- Analyze requirements and write technical documents.
- Provide estimation for CRs in consent with HQ.
- Support in TP IVR development team in developing IVR flows.
- Troubleshoot all report-related issues.
- Customize on-site Huawei applications in coordination with Huawei HQ.



# WorldCall Telecom Ltd, an Oman Tel Company, Lahore

February 2014 to February 2015

### Executive II - Planning & Engineering

- Fiber optic project planning and reporting.
- Develop a dashboard application of all ongoing fiber optic deployment projects for management using VBA for Excel.
- Maintenance of the database of every fiber optic corporate client.

#### Successful Projects

- Telenor Pakistan Contact Center IVR.
- DaaS Platform.
- Successful POC of Google AOG.
- PUBG Voucher Service for Telenor Pakistan.

 APIGEE migration, including backend services.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Spring Framework Ecosystem: Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring Data JPA, Spring Unit/Shallow/Integration Testing
- Angular 2+: Angular Material, NgRx, Scully, Unit/Shallow/Integration Testing for Angular and NgRx
- Python 3, Pandas Library, Data Science using Python
- Shell Scripting
- RDBMS: Postgres, MySQL, Oracle Database
- Understanding of Docker, Git, linting.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **MS Project Management**

August 2019 to March 2021

**University:** Riphah International University, Islamabad

#### **B.E. Electrical**

August 2008 to January 2013

**University:** University of Engineering and Technology, Taxila

## **Intermediate in Computer Sciences (ICS)**

August 2006 to August 2008

**Board:** Federal Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education, Islamabad

# Secondary School Certification (Matriculation)

August 2006

**Board:** Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education, Multan

## SELF ASSESSMENT

- Self-Learner
- Goal Oriented
- Can-do Attitude
- Hard Worker
- Team Player